

EDERSON MORAES

HEAD OF WEB DEVELOPMENT - SCRUM MASTER SPECIALIST AGILE - INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY - DATA ANALYST ♥ PORTO, PORTUGAL

• DETAILS •

Porto Portugal +351 910216333 eder.israel.moraes@gmail.com

• SKILLS •

Project Management

Friendly and Outgoing Attitude

Problem Solving

Excellent Customer Service

Strategic Planning

Multitasking Skills

Network Analysis and Virtualization

Advanced Linux and Servers

Personal Development Coach

Project Structure

Disciplined Agile Scrum Master (DASM)

• TOOLS KNOW-HOW •

Jira | Confluence Zabbix monitoring

Grafana

Metabase BI

Power BI

ower B Gitlab

Expo | EAS

Postman

AWS Platform

Sentry

• HOBBIES •

Dad, Football, Karting, Camping

PROFILE

Everywhere I went, I was always prepared to improve processes, learn and innovate in the way things were done.

I was responsible for ERP operations with units all over Brazil, WEB systems, server maintenance, networks and telephony.

I've worked on creating and implementing server and network infrastructure projects.

I enjoy working in teams with knowledge of technology and who speak the same language.

My last job as a Senior Scrum Master helping teams develop software using Agile Methodologies, where I started as a Web Full Stack, and then improved my skills as a manager and technical leader.

Analyst and developer. MySQL, PostgreSQL, React Native, current Angular and Python enthusiast.

People Management, focus on Productivity and Delivery with Agile methodologies.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Head Of Web Development - Scrum Master specialist Agile at Smartex, Porto - Portugal

February 2020 – February 2024

- Develop software and apps.
- Manage software related projects.
- Architect the structural design of the programs.
- Administration of databases, maintenance of systems and documentation, related to project management, and instruction manuals composition.
- · Automated testing tools and opensource libraries.
- Maintenance of tools used by developers.
- Jira project configuration.
- · Gitlab automations and integrations.
- Use and monitoring of Scrum within projects and teams.
- Teaching and usability within the Scrum Agile Methodology.
- Implementation of new tools to assist developers and project managers.

Technology and Development Manager at Leankeep - Facility Software, Curitiba

July 2017 — December 2019

Project management and new features, with systems analysis. Definition of technologies and architecture.

Organizing technical projects and researching requirements and testing new features with clients.

- Organization and maintenance of tasks and Scrum master in Jira.
- Delivery reports and releases for customers and new products.
- Development feasibility analysis.
- · Estimates and team capacity.
- · Development Analyst.
- Chief Development Officer (CDO).

Senior systems analyst at Seccional Comércio Internacional - Yokohama Brasil, Curitiba

January 2009 — July 2017

Definitions of technologies and organizational infrastructure.

- IT and network analyst.
- · Systems analysis.
- · DevOps Specialist.

Support Analyst at Claro Importadora de Rodas, Curitiba

January 2008 — January 2009

Carrying out the installation, configuration, management and maintenance of computer networks and network equipment, taking into account the techniques and procedures underlying the architecture, planning and design of networks, in order to guarantee their correct and safe operation.

Computer Technician at TSW wheels, Curitiba

January 2007 — January 2008

Hardware and software support, implementation of branches in other states, support for all branches, support for the ERP Softdib system.

• Creating and implementing a virtualization platform to improve system scalability and reduce hardware costs.

Computer Technician at Multilit Fibrocimento, Curitiba

January 2004 — January 2007

- I developed and implemented a backup and recovery plan that guaranteed data integrity in the event of a system failure.
- Writing detailed instructions and procedures for using and maintaining the system, increasing user understanding and self-sufficiency.

Technical support at Softdib, Curitiba - Paraná

January 2003 — January 2004

- Identified and escalated major technical issues to engineering for resolution.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify and resolve customer issues.

EDUCATION

Information System Technology, Opet, Curitiba

January 2006 — December 2008

The planning, management, development, implementation, maintenance, updating, security, optimization and support tasks related to computing solutions are the responsibility of IT professionals.

Analysis and Systems Development, Universidade Tuiuti do Paraná logo Universidade Tuiuti do Paraná, Curitiba

January 2011 — July 2014

The course is focused on the analysis, documentation, and implementation of computer systems. The degree covers the content of analysis, design, systems implementation (focus on web development), database management, computer networks, and operating systems, with the aim of training graduates to work in the development and maintenance of computer systems.

Disciplined Agile Senior Scrum Master, Project Management Institute

September 2022

Disciplined Agile Senior Scrum Master (DASSM) teaches experienced agile practitioners how to use the Disciplined Agile (DA) tool kit to optimize how teams work, work with allies within their organization, and solve a variety of advanced problems.